Santiago Zapata

Hi! My name is Santiago, I'm 23, and I enjoy creating things that live on the internet. I have dedicated the last three years of my life to taught myself software development.

I consider myself a highly motivated, task-driven, self-starting developer seeking to launch a career building web applications and services.

Bogotá, Colombia +57 322 245-7476 entropia@cosmica.dev

cosmicpixel.vercel.app/ github.com/gelatinaCosmica linkedin.com/in/zapata-santiago

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- JavaScript (ES6+)
- TypeScript
- HTML, CSS
- React
- WordPress CMS
- Node JS (Express)
- Serverless (Next, Firebase)
- Deployment (Vercel, Heroku)
- Microsoft Business Central

PROJECTS

Spotify 2.0

Responsive web app built with React using Next JS and Tailwind for visualizing saved playlists, tracks and a fully functional player to play/pause any song.

Airbnb Clone

Web app built with React using Next JS and Tailwind with a simple UI, embedded calendar to filter places by date availavility and Mapbox for places geolocation.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (native)
- English (C2)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Cosmic Pixel | November 2021 - Actual

- Write efficient code using state-of-the-art software development practices
- Coordinate and communicate with customers to plan web development projects from concept through completion, utilizing a variety of web development tools and technology.
- Provide web solutions and develop web sites and web applications based on specific business needs for promotions, presentations, customer service and online services.
- Manage databases and database servers
- · Create and maintain software documentation
- Provide means for scalability of the web application
- Manage, maintain and update existing web sites for customers and provide customer service.

NAV/BC Developer

Logixcare, LLC | February 2021 - November 2021

- Extension development in AL (Application Language) for Microsoft ERP solution Navision (On-Site) & Business Central (Cloud)
- Integrate technologies like Microsoft Dynamics CRM, WooCommerce and Power Platform apps.
- Develop custom API's using the company information to deliver data to external apps.
- · Create custom reports with Microsoft Report Builder
- Mantain and updating customers servers (Windows Server) and Database (SQL Server)
- Refactor legacy code in order to keep all apps up-to-date with the latest version of the ERP.

Junior Web Developer

Trisquelab | April 2019 - November 2020

- Meet with clients to discuss website design and function.
- Design and build the website front-end.
- Create the website architecture.
- Design and manage the website back-end including database and server integration.
- Generate WordPress themes and custom plugins.
- Conduct website performance tests and troubleshoot content issues.
- Monitor the performance of the live website.
- Conduct WordPress training with the client.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Freecodecamp | 2021

Certification course in Algorithms and Data Structures in JavaScript

Back End Development and APIs

Freecodecamp | 2021

Certification course in back end development and APIs with Node.js

Javascript (Basic)

Hackerrank | 2021

Skill certification exam in JavaScript

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp by Colt Steele Udemy | 2020

Certification course in full stack web development with Node.js